

### Contact

#### Phone:

+39 380 699 9491

### E-Mail:

jossmicheal@gmail.com

#### Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yosef-gebremichael-desta-66b71783/

### **Address:**

Via Cesare Colizza 56, Mariono, 00047, RM

## **Skill Highlights**

Technical Leadership
Personnel Management
Project Management
Product Management
Cost and Time Management
Critical thinking
Win as a Team Mindset

# **Technical Skills**

#### Expert:

SAP ABAP, C#, .Net, C++, SAP PI, SQL Intermediate:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SOAP, REST

## Languages

English – Full Professional Proficiency Italian – Elementary Proficiency Amharic – Bilingual Proficiency Tigrigna – Native

# Yosef Gebremichael Desta

Technical Team Leader, Full Stack developer and Project manager with 8+ years of experience in cross-departmental and cross industry. Always looking for new ways, how to grow further and keep a fresh perspective. Has a proven Application development and project management, record of accomplishment of excellence in previous roles of SAP ERP implementation and in-house implemented applications.

### **Experience**

T/Leader SAP ABAP & Integration – Ethiopian Airlines 07/2017 - 11/2021

- Delivering and managing SAP ERP System workflow, Reports, Interfaces, Enhancements and Forms
- Technical Team Lead on ERP Implementation of SAP S/4 HANA for Ethiopian Electric Power
- SAP and other System Integration(Sync and/or A sync) using RFC and Batch Processing
- Project manager of passenger and cargo revenue accounting system for in house system with the responsibility to manage the cost, quality, time, and resource of the whole project.

Senior Application developer – Ethiopian Airlines

11/2013 - 06/2017

- Developed Communication services system automation using C#.Net & Oracle
- Developed Baggage lost and found system using C#.Net and Oracle
- Developed application to encrypt medical history as a module using C# windows form application
- Configured, Monitored and controlled KABA access point system

**Lecturing Experience – Mekelle Inst. Technology** 

10/2012 - 01/2013

Lab Assistant for microcontroller 8051

### Education

**BSc.** Degree

2013

 Computer Science & Engineering, Mekelle Institute of Technology, Ethiopia

# **Certifications**

#### ServiceNow

- Attending NextGen Service Now Program
- Micro Certification on Service Portal and Service Now Fundamentals

#### **Project Management**

- PRINCE2® 2017 Practitioner
- PRINCE2® Foundation Certification